myplan.com 2015-12-28

# MyPlan.com :: Privacy Policy

INTRODUCTION  
MyPlan.com is committed to protecting your privacy. Except as described below and as required by law, we will never knowingly sell, share, loan, rent or otherwise transfer your personal information to others. Put simply — that means we won't sell your personal contact information to others. We take your privacy seriously! And, because we gather certain types of information about our users, we want to help you understand the terms and conditions surrounding the collection and use of that information. This privacy policy discloses the types of information we gather, how we use it, and how you may correct or change it. These privacy practices apply to MyPlan.com and do not cover the privacy practices of our advertisers, business partners or websites that may be linked to from within MyPlan.com.

COLLECTION OF INFORMATION   
Information is collected about you at several different points during your visit to MyPlan.com. The choice of how much personally identifiable information you disclose to us is completely at your discretion. Most areas of our site are accessible without registration or the disclosure of personally identifiable information of any kind. Registration and submission of some personal information is, however, required to access certain areas of our site and to enable certain functionality, personalized in nature to deliver a customized user experience. 

Registration\--Users must register in order to use certain parts of this site. During registration, users are required to provide personal information, including, but not limited to: name, e-mail address, a password, and demographic information. In addition, users may choose to provide other types of personally identifiable information such as occupational or educational information to further customize site functionality.

Community Profile\--MyPlan.com offers its users a rich set of community features including discussion boards, private messaging and user reviews. In order to enable this functionality, provide user interaction, and ensure security from user abuse, each registered user has a basic public profile that identifies them to MyPlan.com and to other users. This basic public profile includes their MyPlan.com username, IP and private message address. In addition, users can also choose to provide additional information on their public profile, such as their location, email address, IM addresses, personal image, and occupation. Any information that you choose to submit to your public profile will be visible to other users of MyPlan.com. Please keep in mind that if you disclose personal information through the MyPlan.com community profile, this information may be collected and used by others. We caution you against providing personal information to strangers online, which they may use for illegal, harmful or spamming purposes. 

Optional Account Information\--Various tools and functionality on the MyPlan.com site require that users provide additional information that we store with their account profile. This optional information includes, but is not limited to: stored portfolio items, personal notes, and assessment test scores. This information is stored in order to enable their corresponding functionality and to ensure that users are able to later retrieve this information. This functionality-based information will never be used to personally identify a user for marketing purposes.

At various other points during your visit to MyPlan.com, you may be asked to provide additional information. For example, you may wish to participate in a survey or to submit a review. Participation in surveys or reviews or the use of other services which require the input of additional information is completely voluntary on your part, and you have the choice about whether to disclose the information necessary to use these features of our site.

Passive Collection of Information\--In addition to the information which you actively provide to MyPlan.com by methods such as registration or survey completion, MyPlan.com collects information about how you interact with our site. MyPlan.com collects passive information for purposes such as testing and improving a user's experience at the site and the compilation of broad aggregate demographic data and related usage information for internal purposes and for disclosure to third parties such as advertisers and content partners. The types of passive information collected by this site include, without limitation, your IP address, which type of browser you are using, where you go on our site, and how long you stay on any part of our site. Passive information does not identify you to MyPlan.com by name, except user IP address which is recorded for security and monitoring purposes.

USE OF COOKIES  
MyPlan.com uses cookies to store visitors' preferences and to record session information. A cookie is a small text file placed on a user's computer hard drive when a user visits a website. The cookie gives the user a unique, random ID, and this ID enables our site to readily recognize each visitor as they page through our site or return on subsequent visits. Cookies enable you to maintain continuity as you move from page to page on MyPlan.com and to avoid the nuisance of being asked to provide the same information repeatedly. Cookies also allow us to make sure that only your browser can exchange information regarding your account with our servers.

We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. You may be able to configure your browser to accept or reject all or some cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set -- each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences -- however, you must enable cookies from MyPlan.com in order to use most functions on our site. Please note that MyPlan.com allows 3rd party advertisers that are presenting advertisements on some of our pages to set and access their cookies on your computer. Advertisers' use of cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not the MyPlan.com Privacy Policy.

USE OF WEB BEACONS  
MyPlan.com pages may contain electronic images known as Web Beacons – sometimes called Web Bugs, transparent gifs, single-pixel gifs, or clear gifs – that allow MyPlan.com to count users who have visited those pages and to deliver co-branded services. MyPlan.com may include Web beacons in promotional e-mail messages or MyPlan.com newsletters in order to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon.

MyPlan.com may also place Web beacons from third parties on our site in order to compile aggregate statistics and to help determine the effectiveness of our joint promotional or advertising campaigns. MyPlan.com prohibits Web beacons on our site from being used by third parties to access your personal information.

COPPA COMPLIANCE  
MyPlan.com complies with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 and with guidelines set up by the Federal Trade Commission regarding youth privacy. As such, MyPlan.com will not knowingly collect any personal information from or allow the registration of persons who are not yet 13 years old. If you are under 13 years of age, you are not authorized to create an account on MyPlan.com, but you can utilize those portions of MyPlan.com that do not involve the collection of personal information from users.

USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION   
We respect your privacy! Except as described below, or as otherwise provided or permitted by law, information collected about you will not be sold, rented, loaned, or otherwise used.

MyPlan.com collects and uses your personally identifiable information in order to operate our site and deliver the services you have requested. These services may include the display of customized content, the generation of test reports, and the operation of the Portfolio Manager. We may also use your personal information to periodically communicate with you. 

Site Enhancements\--The information which you supply to MyPlan.com enables us to continue developing and enhancing our website. When personal information is used in such a manner, users will not be personally identified, except with their expressed and explicit permission (such as in the writing of a review). Most such types of site enhancements involve the use of broad aggregate demographic data and related usage information for the development of content and new functionality.

Site Personalization and Customization\--In addition to site enhancements, MyPlan.com uses personal information to customize or personalize our site for each registered user. MyPlan.com tries to recognize you using various methods including login procedures and cookies. Once recognized, pages, layout, content, and/or advertisements may be customized for you so that you see information that reflects your profile and interests.

Email Communications\--MyPlan.com may use your contact information to periodically communicate with you by email. Such communications may include announcements, newsletters, notifications, and sponsored offerings. All such communications will originate from MyPlan.com and will we never knowingly sell, share, loan, rent or otherwise transfer your personal information to others. You may subscribe or unsubscribe to such communications at any point by visiting the ‘Email Subscriptions’ section of the Account Manager. In addition, all MyPlan.com newsletters and emails also include the above instructions for opting-out of those communications in the future.

Other\--Most other uses of personal information involve aggregate data usage, such as statistical studies and research as well as the development of new products and services. Personal information is also collected and used to complete a transaction such as the purchase of an assessment test license. Note: Credit card and banking information is never stored on our servers; it is merely transmitted to our payment gateway at Authorize.net via 56-bit Secure Sockets Layer encryption.

SHARED ACCESS TO TEST RESULTS  
MyPlan.com allows users to share their career assessment test results with others (including but not limited to the owner of a group license). The choice of whether to share such information and with whom is completely at the discretion of the user. MyPlan.com merely facilitates this sharing of personal information at the direction of the user. Any abuse, grievance, harm, intrusion, or damage that ensues from this exchange of information is the responsibility of the user who expressly requested that such information be shared.

SHARING OF INFORMATION   
We will not knowingly sell, share, loan, rent or otherwise transfer your personal information other than in accordance with the terms set forth in this Privacy Policy.

MyPlan.com will not disclose personal information to any third party unless we believe that disclosure is necessary: (1) to conform to legal requirements or to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other legal process received by MyPlan.com, whether or not a response is required by applicable law; (2) to enforce the MyPlan.com Terms of Use Agreement or to protect our rights; (3) to protect the safety of members of the public and users of our service; or (4) to oblige the user’s expressed desire to share career assessment test results with others. We may, however, share broad aggregate demographic data and related usage information with the public or our business partners. This aggregate information does not contain any personal information which can identify any individual user.

SECURITY   
Security of data is of paramount importance to us. MyPlan.com has rigorous security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, theft, and/or unauthorized alteration of information under our control. You are the only user authorized to update your profile, unless you provide your password information to another party. 

Password Encryption\--User passwords are stored on our servers using one-way 128-bit MD5 hash encryption, meaning that not even we have access to your password. If you lose or forget your password, we are not able to retrieve it; we can only issue you a new temporary password that you must authorize and activate by email.

Payment Information\--While credit card and banking data may be collected in our checkout forms in order to complete a transaction, that information is never stored on our servers. Payment information is transmitted to our transaction gateway at Authorize.net via 56-bit Secure Sockets Layer encryption.

Physical Security of Servers\--Our servers are housed in a co-location facility that is under 24-hour armed guard surveillance, with back-up generators and secured data recovery procedures. Our servers also utilize industry-leading security methods such as firewalls, server passwords, and malicious script scrubbing.

While we take every reasonable and practical measure to ensure the privacy and protection of your data, you should recognize that no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

REVIEWING AND UPDATING PERSONAL INFORMATION  
You can update your personal information by clicking on the "Account" tab at the top of every MyPlan.com page, or by following the instructions included in any e-mail message you receive from MyPlan.com. Users who are experiencing problems with updating their information should contact us at , and we will try to resolve your problems immediately.

COMMUNITY AREAS  
Please be aware that whenever you voluntarily post public information to discussion boards, user reviews, or other community areas of our site, that that information can be accessed by the public and can in turn be used by those people to send you unsolicited communications.

OTHER PROVISIONS   
Acceptance of Terms/Changes to Privacy Policy--Your use of this site indicates an acceptance of the terms of the Privacy Policy. MyPlan.com reserves the right to update or amend this Privacy Policy at any time. 

Disclaimer\--MyPlan.com provides information on many topics. Some of this information is created by MyPlan.com, and some of it is created by third parties. Other information, such as that found in our community areas, is created directly by the users themselves of MyPlan.com. While our site strives to provide accurate expert advice, commentary and other information, MyPlan.com does not make any warranty regarding the accuracy, reliability or use of any information provided on this site. 

Transfer of Ownership\--In the event that MyPlan.com sells, assigns or transfers some or all of its business to a successor or acquirer, MyPlan.com may sell, assign or transfer all of your information, regardless of your opt status, to such successor or acquirer. 

Links to Other Sites\--This site contains numerous links to other sites. Please be aware that MyPlan.com does not exercise control over the information, products, services or policies of third party companies accessible through our site. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy policies of each and every third party site. This Privacy Policy applies solely to the information collected by this site. 

Choice/Opt-out\--You will always have the ability to opt out of receiving emails and other communications from MyPlan.com. We respect your privacy and realize that not everyone likes to receive updates, newsletters, notifications or other communications. Registered users who no longer wish to receive communications may choose to unsubscribe to them by deselecting any or all types of email communications. Simply visit the ‘Email Subscriptions’ section of the Account Manager to subscribe or unsubscribe to our various forms of communications. All MyPlan.com newsletters and emails also include the above instructions for opting-out of those communications in the future.

CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY  
From time to time, we may make changes to our privacy policy. If we make changes, we will post them on our site to make users aware of what the changes are so users will always be aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and when we may disclose it. Users are bound by any minor changes to the policy when they use our site after changes have been posted. If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users by using the word “Updated” next to the Privacy Policy link found at the bottom of every MyPlan.com page (including the home page), and keep such notice posted on our website for 30 days.

QUESTION & COMMENTS  
MyPlan.com welcomes your comments regarding this Privacy Policy. If you have questions about this policy or believe that we have not adhered to it, please contact us at  (MyPlan.com, L.L.C., 11901 Susan Dr., Granada Hills, CA 91344).
